Kashif Ahmad

+91 97098 13874, Kolkata, India

kash151if@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GeeksForGeeks | GitHub

About Me

As a Full Stack Developer with around 2 years of experience in the FMCG sector, I bring a unique combination of technical expertise and industry knowledge to the table. With a strong tech stack that includes React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and Java, I am passionate about problem-solving and have built several cool projects to solve real-world issues.

Work Experience

Software Developer (Jul 2022 - Present)

Greenwave Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata, India

- Led an internal employee service portal for company employees, featuring leave management, claims processing, notifications, and access to salary slips. All senstive values are encypted
- Led the development and redevelopment of multiple modules in the Digital Logbooks and Workflow, which is the product of our company.
- Dockerized multiple monolithic applications and microservices to simplify their deployment, enhance customiz ability, and enable easy deploymen
- Implemented a user authentication and security module that eliminated 100 percent paper logbook usage and enabled sequential workflow of multiple jobs in the industry.
- Configured encrypted database credentials inside the property files using node is API
- Developed a Java application for multiple clients to transfer data between PostgreSQL, MS SQL, MySQL, OracleDB and MongoDB databases. The application was integrated with a scheduler to automate the data transfer process at regular intervals.

Tech stack in use: React.js, Node.js, Redux, Java, Spring Boot, JSF, SQL, PotgreSQL, Docker, jwt, bcrypt.

Assiociate Software Developer (June 2022 - Present)

Greenwave Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata, India

- Led the transformation of a large JSF monolith to microservices using React and Spring Boot and implemented real-time data visualization with web socket integration.
- Utilized JavaScript's event loop concept to optimize page load time. and by breaking down each
 component of the page into separate responsibilities, page load time was reduced by around 50
 percent (up to 90 percent for larger datasets).
- Created robust APIs in Node.js for end-to-end data transfer and client-facing REST APIs for seamless
 interaction with the products.
- Developed the backend for a PTC Thingworx platform for a client.

Tech stack used: React.js, Node.js, Redux, Graphql, TypeScript, JavaScript, MsSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL Socket.IO, Java, Chart.js, Express.js, JSF, HTML, CSS, Mui

Software Intern (April 2021 - June 2021)

Greenwave Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata, India

- Worked as an SQL and Thingworx developer .
- Improved reporting rates by developing dashboard and reporting system on PTC Thingworx

Tech stack used: JavaScript, SQL, PTC Thingworx, React.js.

Education

B. Tech. in Computer Science, University of Calcutta, (June 2021)

Skills

Libraries

Programming Languages

JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS

Frameworks and

Node.js, React.js, Spring Boot, Express.js, JSF-Primefaces, PrimefaceReact,

Bootstrap, Mui, Chart.js, React.native, Vue.js, Socket.IO

Database MySQL, MS SQL, PostgreSQL, PL/PGSQL, MongoDB, Firebase

Other Technologies Docker, Git, GitHub, SVN, PTC Thingworx

Personal Projects

- Custom Components A set of custom React components, including dynamic tables, responsive carousels, pop-ups, and more, designed for easy customization and use. Further expansion will include features like diagrams and organization charts.
- Meal Booking System (Online food order) An advanced web app for meal booking in
 hostels/offices with user-friendly features including meal tracking, billing, and a dashboard. Admins
 manage meals, expenses, generate bills/reports, and mail bills with ease. Efficient for users and
 admins, with Excel data downloads.
- Online Exam Portal An online exam portal for convenient exams. Admins add questions via Excel, and the platform tracks user behavior for insights and integrity along with time.
- Flat Expense Records (Split App) A React-based expense tracker with Firebase backend, similar to Split app. It features dark and light mode options, allowing users to manage expenses, track multiple users, and generate insightful reports.
- **Study Planner** A React-based expense tracker with Firebase backend, similar to Split app. It features dark and light mode options, allowing users to manage expenses, track multiple users, and generate insightful reports.
- **Snake and Ladder** A Full Stack real time muiltiplayer snake and ladder game built using HTML, CSS and Vue.js for Front End and Firebase Firestore for realtime database.
- Covid-19 tracker A responsive web-app made in Vue.js with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap as front-end, used library such as Map-box GL, Chart.js also used Covid19India and covid19 API for real-time data
- All Projects A responsive web-app made in Vue.js with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap as front-end, used library such as Map-box GL, Chart.js also used Covid19India and covid19 API for real-time data